Guide to the Thomas E. Marston Family Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Thomas E. Marston family papers
1711-1981
1938-1954
GEN MSS 1341
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
2.3
(6 boxes)
The Thomas E. Marston Family Papers contain Marston family correspondence and a small amount of material relating to Thomas E. Marston's collecting of medieval and early modern books and manuscripts, and his association with the Yale University Library. Most family correspondence consists of letters to Julia Dale Ewart Marston from Josephine Sands Marston, 1938-1951, concerning family news; accompanying these are letters from Thomas E. Marston and their children, Josephine Ewart Marston and Thomas Marston, and photographs of the children. Other correspondence of Julia Dale Ewart Marston includes additional letters from Thomas E. Marston, 1951-1954, concerning his divorce from Josephine Sands Marston, and letters from other members of the Marston and Sands families, 1923-1964. Papers of Thomas E. Marston include correspondence, 1957-1981 and undated, most with book and manuscript vendors or Yale University colleagues; and writings and research materials, 1945-1976 and undated. Research materials include a copy of The Spectator, number CCVII, 1711 October 27.
Marston, Thomas E.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Minna Reese Marston, 2008.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Thomas E. Marston (1904-1984) (Yale 1927)
Thomas E. (Thomas Ewart) Marston, collector of medieval and early modern books and manuscripts, particularly early modern editions of classical literature; donor of medieval and early modern books and manuscripts to the Yale University Library; and Yale University Library Associates trustee, 1933-1984. In 1935 Marston was appointed assistant to the Keeper of Rare Books at Yale, and he later served as curator of medieval and Renaissance literature, retiring in 1973. Marston was the son of Julia Dale Ewart Marston and Thomas B. (Thomas Brunton) Marston, (born 1857; Yale 1879). He married Josephine Sands, daughter of Benjamin J. (Benjamin Jerome) Sands and Josephine W. Sands, in 1938. They had two children, Josephine Ewart Marston Bringe and Thomas Marston (1944-2011). Thomas E. Marston and Josephine W. Sands were divorced in 1938. Marston married Minna Reese in 1963.
Scope and Contents
The Thomas E. Marston Family Papers contain Marston family correspondence and a small amount of material relating to Thomas E. Marston's collecting of medieval and early modern books and manuscripts, and his association with the Yale University Library. Most family correspondence consists of letters to Julia Dale Ewart Marston from Josephine Sands Marston, 1938-1951, concerning family news; accompanying these are letters from Thomas E. Marston and their children, Josephine Ewart Marston and Thomas Marston, and photographs of the children. Other correspondence of Julia Dale Ewart Marston includes additional letters from Thomas E. Marston, 1951-1954, concerning his divorce from Josephine Sands Marston, and letters from other members of the Marston and Sands families, 1923-1964. Papers of Thomas E. Marston include correspondence, 1957-1981 and undated, most with book and manuscript vendors or Yale University colleagues; and writings and research materials, 1945-1976 and undated. Research materials include a copy of The Spectator, number CCVII, 1711 October 27.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: Julia Dale Ewart Marston Papers, 1923-1964. II. Thomas E. Marston Papers, 1711-1981.
Book collecting -- United States; Book collectors -- United States; Librarians -- United States; Manuscripts -- Collectors and collecting -- United States; Photographs -- United States -- 20th Century; Book collectors -- United States -- 20th Century; Librarians -- United States -- 20th Century; Anne-Marie von Schutzbar gennant Milchling, Hereditary Duchess of Oldenburg, 1903-1991; Bringe, Josephine Ewart Marston; Marsden family; Marston, Josephine J. Sands; Marston, Julia Dale Ewart; Marston, Rose; Marston, Thomas B. (Thomas Brunton); Marston, Thomas E.; Sands family; Yale University. Library
- Julia Dale Ewart Marston Papers, 1923-1964; Series I; 1.88; (5 boxes)
  - Letters from Josephine J. Sands Marston and Thomas E. Marston
    - Letters, [circa 1923]-1927 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Letters, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Letters, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Letters, 1941 January-March (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Letters, 1941 April-July (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Letters, 1941 August-October (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Letters, 1941 November-December (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Letters, 1942 January-May (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Letters, 1942 June-September (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Letters, 1942 October-December (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Letters, 1943 January-April (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Letters, 1943 May-October (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Letters, 1943 November-December (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Letters, 1944 January-April (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Letters, 1944 May-August (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Letters, 1944 September-December (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Letters, 1945 January-May (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Letters, 1945 June-August (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Letters, 1945 September-December (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Letters, 1946 January-April (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Letters, 1946 July-September (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Letters, 1946 October-December (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Letters, 1947 January-April (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Letters, 1947 May-December (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Letters, 1948 January-March (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Letters, 1948 April-June (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Letters, 1948 July-August (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Letters, 1948 September-December (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Letters, 1949 January-March (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Letters, 1949 April-August (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Letters, 1949 September-December (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Letters, 1950 January-March (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Letters, 1950 April-July (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Letters, 1950 August-December (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Letters, 1951 January-August (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Letters, 1951 September-December (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Letters, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Letters, 1953-1954 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Letters, undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Other Correspondence
    - Anne-Marie von Schutzbar gennant Milchling, Hereditary Duchess of Oldenburg, 1948-1964, undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Marston, Rose, 1949, undated (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Marston, Thomas B., 1922 May 13 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Marston, Thomas B. (to Emma Louise Catherwood Marston), 1920 January 11 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Sands, Josephine W., 1940-1946 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Sands, Josephine W., 1947-1949 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Sands, Josephine W., 1950-1951, undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Sands, Josephine W., undated (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Photographs
    - Marston, Thomas E., 1935 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Bringe, Josephine Ewart Marston; and Marston, Thomas (1944-2011), 1942, undated (Box 5, Folder 50)
- Thomas E. Marston Papers, 1973 - 1981; Series II; 0.42; (1 box)
  - Correspondence, 1957-1973 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Correspondence, 1974-1981, undated (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Writings, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Juvenal. Satura. Essay by Joseph Addison in The Spectator (number CCVII), 1711 October 27 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Juvenal. Satura. Other research materials, undated (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Yale University Library exhibitions, 1947, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Yale University Library press releases, 1968-1974 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Other research materials, 1966-1972 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Other research materials, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Other research materials, undated (Box 6, Folder 60-61)
  - Other papers, 1940, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 62)